

## Austin, TX 78727 | (H) (512) 921-4843 | (C) (512) 921-4843 | cycdaniel@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

Goal-oriented Web Developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Use various web design software to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of end-users. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

## Skills

- Certified Professional Web Developer
- Web development
- Programming

- HTML/CSS/JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Python, #C,
- Operating Systems & Technical Support
- Troubleshooting & Website Optimization

## Work History

# Web Developer Boot Camp Student

08/2019 to 11/2019

**UT Austin** – Austin, Texas

- Used various technologies to make code repairs and optimize corporate website
- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for multiple websites
- Created eye-catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity
- Oversaw troubleshooting of technical issues to solve problems quickly and efficiently
- Utilized Visual Studio Code to design and develop 20+ web applications deploying them to GitHub/Heroku
- Designed sites to be compatible with top browsers, including Firefox, Chrome, and Safari
- Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment
- Collaborated with software engineer on projects to gain exposure on real-world workflow experience

#### **Senior Accountant**

02/2017 to 08/2019

### **Southwest Key Programs** – Austin, TX

- Implemented use of various software to enter project data, analyze and track budgets, evaluate project costs and monitor performance trends
- Handled month-end and year-end end finances by managing and reporting fixed assets and other data
- Reviewed budgets, including capital appropriations and operating budgets, and communicated findings to senior management
- Prepared accounts for industry audits and supported audit process
- Automated manual review process before payroll run by customizing exception reports in ERP software
- Investigated and resolved variances in digital and physical records to promote record integrity
- Developed reconciliation processes for A/P and A/R department to identify discrepancies which resulted in tremendous time saving

## **Financial Accountant**

04/2014 to 02/2017

## **Southwest Key Programs** – Austin, TX

- Led daily general ledger entries, using double-entry accounting method and check backs
- Mitigated impacts on financial accounting and business operations by working proactively to identify and resolve strategic concerns
- Reconciled credit card transactions on bank statement against the transactions processed in the accounting system for over \$20MM
- Streamlined bank reconciliation procedures which resulted in an increase of accuracy
- Enhanced customer satisfaction by uncovering and correcting outstanding financial problems
- Collected and arranged financial information and entered details into the financial management system

## Education

**Certificate**: Full-Stack Web Developer Boot Camp Certificate **University of Texas At Austin** - Austin, TX

11/2019

12/2012

BBA: Finance

Texas State University - San Marcos, TX